michael/smith

michael@eightnine.co / eightnine.co/smith / (404) 661-6558

Professional Focus

While professionally titled as a front-end architect, I strive to bridge the gap between design and development by pairing years of front-end development experience with over a decade of visual design expertise. My primary tech focus lies in architecting & building complex, eye-catching, and scalable React + Redux web apps, though I'm no stranger to utilizing other technologies to ensure quality project deliverables. Beyond pure delivery skills, I've successfully lead teams of junior and senior developers, worked closely with product owners for global corporations, and stepped into almost every role in the agile development process to ensure a project's success.

Experience

Front-End Architect

2021 — Current

MERGE — Chicago, IL

As a front-end architect with MERGE Chicago, I've worked to grow the EEP department's front-end team and allow MERGE to produce complex, cutting-edge web apps and significantly increase repeat client engagement. Beyond growing the EEP department, I've continued to architect & deliver high quality front-end work for our clients.

Lead Interactive Developer

2017 - 2021

Isobar — Chicago, IL

As a lead developer with Isobar, I focused primarily on building React + Redux web applications for the US Air Force and Enterprise Car Rentals suite of brands. I architected and lead numerous projects and feature releases for both clients, and worked seamlessly within larger teams to coordinate significant releases and milestones.

Senior UI Developer

2014 — 2017

Dunn Solutions Group — Skokie, IL

As a senior UI Developer at Dunn Solutions Group I built a wide variety of dynamic, fully responsive portals & e-commerce sites for clients that ranged from global cosmetic companies to hospital chains. I led the front-end development & UI design efforts for many of these projects from inception to completion, working directly with our clients.

Education

DePaul University

2014

Chicago, IL

Bachelor's Degree in Interactive Media — Concentration in Interaction Design